oh yeah
give me six reasons why software bellman
doesn't suck so you can't do it
everybody agrees it's off and there's a
lot of reasons for this one is like
technical getting computers to do what
you want them to do can be very
difficult but mostly it's humans humans
are really strange people you're gonna
deal with like managers you gotta do
with meeting scheduling deadlines all
this stuff and that's really what makes
software development tricky it becomes
sort of a problem to have to deal with
all this sort of stuff and people have
come up with ways to deal with this as
best as they can
these are things with you know agile
waterfall pair programming BDD TDD all
that stuff whatever is popular at that
given moment and I've tried all of them
and if they're work for you that's great
the software development is hard but for
those of us
okay for those of us who don't buy into
the whole agile stuff it sucks because I
want to do that guy who's really into
their process and into their workflow
because if you're gonna identify with
something that works really well for you
that's amazing and for the longest time
I thought I was just weird I still do
and I just you know I wanted something
that really worked well for me and I
think to the point the last year or two
at github we've sort of come down and
figured our development process that is
really interesting it doesn't feel like
process it's really quick it's really
fast
it scales really well and that's why I
want to talk about today so this is not
the Safari all sort of this this is how
again it uses github to build github the
secret here is that this isn't really
about github online I used to get up
three times in the title so it's sort of
blog github but what I mean by that is
that this is not about github the tool
you know I'll talk about get up the tool
because it's easy to use it as an
example for stuff but I really want to
talk about our workflow our process and
how we use our tools and come and choose
our schools and why that makes for a
really fun development environment so I
don't think this is really about github
if I work for Twitter I would give the
same talk about work for Facebook I want
to get the same talk I want this to be a
talk for making you think about how your
company can use the processes and
workflows that we use to improve your
own product
so I'm Zach Coleman a woman on Twitter a
moment I get hub I do work for github
it's a social coding site I'm employee
number nine so I've been there for about
a year and a half now and we're now 46
47 employees so we've grown a lot and
I've been able to be there for a year
and a half and see what hasn't worked
out for us how we've changed our
workflow and more importantly what has
worked for us what assumptions have
remained in beginning that we've been
able to keep with us the entire time so
first of all I want to talk about a
little bit about how we work otherwise
this talk will probably sound the same
the big part of what we do is we work
asynchronously
so what does this actually mean I look
this up in a dictionary
and I said you can do without
needing to pull me out of this element
I read real edgy dictionaries but it's
what's so important for us is that
getting people in the zone is really
important this is the difference between
going to work and you're not in the zone
and you're trying to constantly battle
and try to you know force yourself to
write code and it's one of those cases
where you know throwing hours at the
problem doesn't solve things with
software development you want to be in
the zone because when you're in the zone
you can do as much an hour as you can
you know 20 hours out of the sounds so
we want to get more people in the zone
or our employees as much as possible and
do that we have no meetings no deadlines
no managers which is you know kind of
insane you can do it to fire all the
managers it's it goes back to this
really works for us it's a very fun
place to work because it gives people in
the zone as much as possible so what
does that what do I mean by that one
chatrooms we do everything in chat room
this sort of stems from one get up as a
three-person company and did everything
online we didn't have an office for the
first too much years and this really
bring it's through everything if it's
you and me at the office at 2:00 in the
morning no one else is around we're at
the same table we're still going to talk
in the chat room the reason for that is
that personally it lets everybody see
what's going on there's a lot more
visibility in the company I can go out
to lunch
I can go to Kansas City and when I come
back whenever I got internet I can see
exactly what happened the company in the
specific areas and it's a much easier
way of like letting everybody get
involved and there's no more secret
projects where only oh that guy knows
that project you'll have to talk to him
and arrange a time because that sucks
yes it depends so as an aside we have a
bunch of campfire rooms we have like
twenty or thirty now I don't read the
danger room because that's all the enemy
to gist and cubot reign supreme
that's insane but specific ones where
I'm really involved with like you don't
have enterprise I'll go back and read
the transcript from the last few days
and stuff like that we want to break out
as much as possible in separate groups
and then it becomes much more manageable
to see what's going on and your domain
of responsibilities and then lastly time
flexibility work when you want to work
this is really important we have a lot
of people coming in the office at like
6:00 in the morning that's definitely
not me because I'm not productive at
that point like we want people to be
productive as much as they can and some
people are super productive in the
morning and they cannot assume work at
night and that's cool
I'm totally the opposite and mandating
that you have to come in a certain time
and leave those a certain time just
damages that this brings people out of
the zone so I wrote about this three
parts and stuff you want to check that
out you can but I want to get on to
actual other stuff let's talk about flow
requested branching I think this is a
huge part of what github of course as
well as we do I'll talk about issues I
want to talk about OAuth is identity
hooks and hewlet and secrets so first we
request some branching this is sort of
the most interesting part of github I
think you guys have really weird
branches and I see the support requests
come in and someone has detailed their
process and like your job just kind of
troughs each paragraph like how do you
work in this fashion and like about this
I mean like there's one company I saw
was a master branch makes sense then
they cut a deploy branch every time they
wanted to deploy makes sense but then
they just cut a deployed branch off of
each individual deploy branch so by the
end of this you have no idea where the
hell you are
this is just insane it's overly
complicated you don't need to do this
stuff more likely I see this a lot in
large enterprise companies you have a
repository that you work on then you
have a group
trusted developers these are the guys
with full rewrite access to the repo and
they can do whatever they want and then
you have a group this I thought we
should be developers because there
obviously must be shitty if they put
them in this separate side and they only
give them read access and they're trying
to sell all these arbitrary guidelines
it just seems really insane to me so
what you have is like they all have to
port their own projects from the main
repository all those Forks that have to
go back to the trust developers for them
to figure out okay is this good to go
back in the real repository it's not
making us image the Shiva lovers and
then they pulled on new changes to the
repository if you see a chart like this
in your organisation's something is
up keep your branches simple I
think this is really important this is
fundamentally important this is sort of
the foundation where you build your
product all right no controlling you
know you mean the stuff I was going to
cover in the next minute
you know so keep your branches simple
branches should be simple let's talk
about how we do branching because I
think obviously we have a perfect
branching situation here document what
we have is a master branch and then we
have a branch where you work on a bug
fix or a feature or anything like that
when you're done with that that goes a
master this is it that's the entire
branching strategy we don't really
branch off with separate branches or do
anything more complex than this and it
becomes a lot easier to bring out
somebody new and just sail where you cut
a branch when that's ready to go in push
the master along with that every push
everyone deploy our designer on their
first day can deploy to github we have a
lot of automation surrounding 2.2 the
50-plus servers we have now and that's
good we want people to have
responsibility over the code that they
actually write too many times you have
something more like a release manager
where you push it with a really release
manager and then that becomes their
responsibility for the stuff we want
people who write the stuff to be
responsible this also frees yourself up
from micromanaging other people's code
the trust developers in the shade
developers part you want people to be
responsible for their own code for us
master is always employable this is like
the one part of rule that is constant at
github if you push the master a sua can
be deployed as soon as it passes CI the
reason we do this is because we deploy
10 to 40 times a day we like very short
changes and it's something breaks you
know exactly what breaks really quickly
if you're nervous you employed a staging
we have separate staging environment we
can also deploy separate branches and
test that out and deploy the master
afterwards
you know so the point of stuff set so if
you could say like let me just deploy
two boxes right away and see if anything
blows up if it doesn't inversion in the
master
from there this is also sort of Twitter
driven development because you guys are
way more on top of things than we are
sometimes and like people will tweet
constantly if something breaks now we
have like graphs and stuff we're like
you know number of exceptions and then
deploy is really marked on the graph and
then we mark that against every flies to
get love on Twitter and it's actually
very proportional to you know you break
something people will talk about it so
keep your branches simple that's really
important I know what you guys are
thinking you know what about code
equality the other designer in
there messing with your code
no one likes designers they do weird
stuff so we'll how do you keep up code
quality and our response to that is pull
requests this is central to everything
we do pull requests our code review what
are Laurie bus tour bus our discussion
it's a simple discussion about a piece
of code indistinct piece of code it's a
discussion about codes just mention
about that particular feature discussion
about that particular strategy all this
stuff comes together you can do a bunch
of different stuff to it you can
reference issues in it you can reference
other bits of code disks in it you can
write code comments it's all about
figuring out how you make a discussion
on piece of code and then from that
point you can figure out do you want
this in the actual code base all this
stuff happens on a separate branch so
none of the stuff ends up being
dangerous because it's separate from
your production code until it's ready
this is what it looks like I'm sure most
of you guys actually know what Laurie
quests are but you know it's title
description and bunch of commits once
those commits are done that you can
discuss on those commits and discuss
them more than you commit and then you
get merged back into the master
whatever branch that you're trying to
version into the poultry bus itself is
broken out into a discussion where you
can actually talk about the changes the
commits or you show the commits and then
the diff where you can actually see what
has actually changed in the code and
this is really cool because we're really
large to get up at this point and no one
person can really take it to every line
of code that's changed but it's
important that you have a lot of people
know what you're doing so for a lot of
claw requests I won't look at the actual
code I'll just look at the discussion
and see like the title description and
that's a good way it's sort of like an
RSS of what development is happening
without having to sit down and do a
stand-up meeting or anything like that I
can just see it in my inbox as it goes
by and it's very simple
so I lied this isn't actually our
development strategy it's more similar
to this where you branch off send the
port west and then merge it in the
master and that's sort of the guard
against any really shitty code deployed
accidentally so vixa kind of one you
don't need a fork anything this is sort
of our common misconception you can do
poor request between branches on the
same repo and that's what we do
consistently and give up we don't fork
the main github repo all the time we're
just do pork was between into more
individual branches and then you have to
set up weird permission strategies to
let people under your different force
and stuff it's just a much simpler way
to do things
so why employed was actually rad for
reasons one they're asynchronous no
meetings
everybody's had that time where you're
in a cobra do in person and you're
projecting code on the wall you're
trying to figure out like okay you're
running it through your MRI in your head
you're trying to figure out okay this
compiles to this and does this it's a
terrible way of reviewing code with poor
requests you can easily pull down the
diff and run it locally and you can do
that whenever you want you don't have to
have a separate meeting on that stuff
it's really helpful to have it broken
away from some sort of synchronous like
this has to get reviewed right now and
stuff like that
certainly emails a good interface for
this too when I wake up in the morning I
can see all blow requests of a generator
from Europe for example and so again
this is a quite easy way to figure out
what's going on in the company without
mandating some standup which doesn't
even work when half your team is across
the world they're also really accessible
and we use this a lot
designers evolve entire mock-ups in
imploring words and that's really
powerful too it's like sort of merging
control for a mock-up so you can see as
you go along what what the mock-up has
changed over time to keep discuss on
that - we also have a bunch of
non-technical staff like we have a
shipper who ships out all your beautiful
shop stuff and she can go in and check
out a flurry quest like this is gonna
change the shop get up calm site can you
actually say like does this make sense
yeah she doesn't have to go see the code
did but she can see what's actually
happening and check it out they're also
historical making the experiments in
this should be experiments we have a lot
of pull requests that are designed not
to ever get deployed because we want to
see okay what do you guys think about
this interface what do you think about
this API like this does make sense it
does then I can just close the floor
request and then actually build it for
real don't be afraid to try something
out throw it away because it retains the
history and they should be really fun to
make you should not have to fear about
doing some insane experiment when you're
drunk and seeing how it works out so I
want to show you just a couple point
four requests that we do at github it's
a little bit more context static demo
calm there was a problem a while ago
again were you guys caught stuff before
we did or more or correctly we would get
like the notifications that something is
down but it took us another couple
minutes to actually update the status ID
so I added something just real time
pulling of different services on
github.com just to see if they're up and
this is a pull request now started out
just with a bare-bones interface and I
just dumped this on a page it would
check this and I didn't have to care
about styling or anything like that
because I knew it once I posted this
summer would come in and be like I want
to design that and that's where we have
a lot where designers
just gonna sort of you know see what's
happening the company and when it's
ready for them to come in they'll do a
design at that point I have a design act
build on that and commit to that design
and then just match it and it's very
easy for me I never have to worry about
that in the slightest and there's no
love front meetings it just all happens
very asynchronously by the end of it we
close it merchant shipping and that's it
it's very simple very easy you should
not be afraid to mix your designers and
developers they should work together
just like or bus are kind of scary from
a designer's point of view but they
don't have to get into the nitty-gritty
if they don't want to it's it's helpful
for them to get into the discussion
section don't be pretty close
screenshots a lot you can use you can
use this in the markdown which I'll show
you in a couple seconds but it's very
good to be very visual even on back-end
stuff you can also post gifs because
they're funny we do that a lot we also
have something called code editing or
it's a syntax highlighting in your code
editor and this was like earlier this
year and this entire pull request we did
all this stuff did this bunch of
discussion and then we're like
it doesn't work we can't do it close it
and that's it that's important that's
still really good because they're cheap
as hell you shouldn't be afraid to
experiment that seemed really kind of a
bummer at first this we really wanted
this to work out but the library we were
using didn't work out don't be afraid to
toss it away this was great because five
or six months later we found a different
library that did a lot better and
integrins and it works how we wanted it
to work and we could go back to the
original claw request and say what was
my design decisions here what did I
wanted to hear and then you don't have
to reinvent the wheel every time so
really play around pull request visible
request that started the beginning this
year hasn't shipped yet it's got a bunch
of stuff in it and that's really cool we
can hire somebody tomorrow and if
they're asking what they want to work on
we can point them to this there's no you
know back alleyway deals about like you
know communicate between two people then
they need to have to chase down somebody
else if you like please tell me what
your thoughts are on this
it's all right here we can go back later
to check it out kitchens done don't
waste your time
just this is something that you have to
constantly worry about like can you
would improve your workflow can you make
it a lot better and it's something that
you have to do constantly because
otherwise will sneak up on you and
really you down the road so recap
news pull request more they're awesome
ship a lot more I think they're really
great I think they're really important
and if you are able to do them in your
company
I should investigate almost I go to
choose everybody has issues of different
companies I'm talking about like tickets
stuff like that
so everybody see the screen like this
like a new issue create screen the
problem of this is there's a lot of
stuff going on here and some of the
makes sense and you're like okay yeah
that's cool and then they just layer
more and more stuff on there before you
know what there's some up
going on there turn figure out what is
what is the point of all this stuff like
duplicating priorities and stuff like
that this is the one and you know calm
and this is not again about get up this
is the tool we choose internally all it
is is title description and we do away
with a whole bunch of priorities and
craziness because for the most part you
don't need to ask you something about
survival simpler tools can work better
and faster on simpler tools I think you
can brother man I sort of have a man
crush on him Twitter crush these amazing
hero this awesome post on email
priorities they said the priorities was
they're not manufacturer signing
otherwise necessarily not a priority
making something a big red top topic
highest number one priority changes
nothing but textile we're really
important there would be done period I
think that's really important he's
talked about email but the same is true
for stuff across the board issues
prioritization dragging dropping like
all these issues to prioritize and stuff
think about if you actually need that if
you do that's cool then use it but if
you don't need that you're wasting a lot
of time there's all this stuff that we
have as developers asking to get rid of
all of it resist any metal work it gets
in the way of real work the real work
will get done quickly your we use issues
for three things should something broken
something is broken that gets fixed in
few hours that's it we also use issues
or wouldn't it be cool if and then you
it's nice to have a discussion this is
prior to the flooring quest because you
don't want to throw it on code yet but
it's fun to talk about we also use as
to-do lists sometimes that's just kind
of an easy way you don't have to set up
a weird you know issue tracking you know
to do report or something like that it's
all just one in one issue do you need
more than that really think about that
the most time you don't sometimes you do
which is fine almost of time you don't
simple tools means a better product
because you can build it simpler okay oh
office identity this is fun
I love Ruby I really love Ruby I'm not
talking about like the speed of Ruby
because it is slow sticks I'm talking
about like how fast is to build
something like it is really fast and
build something so I looked through my
development folder about what projects I
have in there and I have one called
Secretary of Labor all caps I was really
drunk when I wrote this and I saw in the
next morning it's just a signal Sinatra
app and it's got a stuff referential
symlink called what that points to
itself I have no idea what it does I
have one called unmarked van which
attracts people's physical locations a
one called trace is a real-time stats
graphing in Redis the point is all this
stuff is really fun to make it was fun
experiment none of this stuff is ever
shipping especially not that first one
but it's fun to try stuff out and we do
this stuff and give up too we have a
bunch of internal apps we have you know
probably have more than this at this
point but some of them are more fun some
of them are very serious ci stuff like
that we have an internal Twitter which
is more fun status updates and stuff
like that the point is that we want
people experimenting keeps things really
funny keeps things interesting the
problem with all this is that Outsiders
aren't welcome like we're really open
company but you don't wants people just
trudging through all your stuff so yeah
that's an authentication layer for us we
use github for that medication layer we
have all of our team's our orgs in give
up so we just use a lot to attempt that
and use that as sort of medication and
all of these separate mini apps you guys
what we all see in the screen the you
know a lot of them to check out your
profile
yes no you can use this in a bunch of
different ways there's a whole bunch of
different Ruby libraries this is one
done by Atmos all we have to do is just
check whether or not they're a member of
the github or if they are lemon in the
app it's very easy if we you know hire
somebody we don't have to update 30 40
different apps we have it's all in one
place it's just a nice consistent way of
doing things think about like if you
have this problem can you pawn it off on
somebody else and that means github a
lot of people on Twitter now you can use
Twitter's authentication for that or you
know if you're big enough to have your
own it internally that server or
whatever you got just don't reinvent the
wheel it's good to use a consolidated
feature for all this stuff okay let's
talk about cubot everybody what you
bought so free so you bots are friendly
campfire bots he's cool even do some
stuff the other trainer commands for us
employer github app this is important
when you have 50 some servers because
you have no idea how to employ all that
stuff so we just say you might deploy
exit to production and he doesn't that's
great
I mean you're on branch level tests so
if you push the branch up that will just
run automatically if like using in the
office and you tell us who is in the
office based on a white/black presence
on their MAC address on their phone or
their laptop bill abusive drastic in
charge all those exceptions for such
deploys versus Twitter mentions send
receive text messages your mustache
every image posted chat like that
attract who swears the most every day
you know we can do all this stuff and
it's more fun because it's a shared side
project again and it's fun to have
experimentation use cool technologies
it's too bad he's not open source I'm
sorry is that open source that's look
like last week it's awesome we have like
tons of adapters now using IRC campfire
XMPP and tons of stuff so check them out
if you haven't already this is a really
fun project you have it
your company in terms of how we use them
for github we use them a bunch of
different ways specifically we use them
for branch status a lot you're gonna ask
you about what hasn't been deployed and
he'll return it and compare view of what
has been deployed yet so you know if
you're gonna deploy this these are the
concrete disks that have been deployed
yet and be worried about these if you
deploy we can do this on a different
branch to surgery and deploy a separate
branch to production or you know you
want to know what on that branch has
been version master yet you can do all
this it all stems from this shop which
we know what does the currently deployed
code on github because it's all in this
one site it's just an endpoint and use
this all over the place like CI stuff
like that
it's just a nice helpful way of doing
that and you can build it with your pair
of use and it's fun because he was long
the API and get up to I can ask it one
of the Pollard bus on my particular
repository and I'll sit back all the
quarry quests very simple very easy it
becomes a nice way of setting the to-do
list if you're ever like what should I
work on today this is nice way to start
we also have the same thing for issues
we have bug days every like second
Thursday or so just as a way to clear
out little issues and this is kind of
fun you can ask it humming it's doing
close to it and you know I'm back how
many issues you close today it's another
way it's sort of you know I hate the
word but like gamification of like your
work it's fun to be like how can we do
more issues knocked out this week than
we did the last time it's fun
think about what you can automate at
your company because the stuff that
really sucks are the things that you
have to repeatedly do over and over
again and we're developers it's it's fun
to of over-engineer stuff sometimes and
like you'll spend way more time
automating something then you think
you'll get out of it but you'll actually
get a lot more out of it than you
probably think
plus it's really fun to do so the moral
of story about knows we live I don't
know he's freaking finally I just want
to talk about some cigarettes I don't
blow through these because github got
some funny secrets we talk stuff away
sometimes our bad here's the fun stuff
you can have emoji all those fun things
we do these I'm flow requests all the
time we just
one stuff we say art I don't know it's
fun it's a fun way of getting people
involved on stuff really cool go to that
link to see a whole list of emoji and
stuff like that all my slides are up on
my site later you can check out these
links and stuff later shortcuts if you
guys don't know all this stuff W will
bring up the branch selector on a repo
page he will do the finding project sort
of like the text mining project really
quick I mean you can press a question
mark on any page you'll bring up the
help dialog and those like crap-ton of
the shortcuts you can do to do a bunch
of different stuff issues for example
has a whole bunch of quick access to
issues images images are awesome
especially when they're animated this is
the markdown format for posting an image
into issues this will post the image on
force this only works if you dorky
dodgeball team is the image I'm just
kidding that's our basketball team dodge
well we waited 50 grand it was great for
charity not broken also different patch
I mean it was based on a mailing list
point of view so all of this stuff that
we expose on github is also available in
text basically to just add get the duck
tip or dot patch after most URLs and
will spit out a nice thing that you can
put directly to get later the other
thing we have is Sprint's code this is
sort of a you did the formatting of any
code that you can taste into issues or
requests stuff like that all you have to
do is triple tick and then say what
language you want and it will syntax
highlight for that language a nice quick
thing to do especially doing in read
these because read knees would just
blocks of code in them kind of sucks
it's nice to have that syntactically
highlighted mentions we use this a lot
they're gonna open a issue we usually
add like CC you know at TechnoMarine e
or at defunct and then that will notify
them and get them to put their eyes on
your floor request it's a nice way of
just having communication amongst your
requests issues stuff like that whites
facing that question mark w equals one
to reduce whitespace and disks
sometimes that's really help
of some dice an employer requests with a
whole bunch of whitespace changes and
you're like I don't even know like
changing what needs a way to do that
repo references you can cross you can
reference issues and pull requests
across different repositories so you
just in your issue body just say like
user sorry mode and number of signed
issues and that will bring in the link
on the referenced issue and it'll just
connect the two visually in the webpage
it's kind of nice I have a sumo
announcement right now we have a URL
shortener we've been using for a while
now I'm announcing this here because I
can so if you have a really long URL you
can shorten it to get that IOU RL you do
that via this is a very simple service
the the Ren URL down there is actually a
gist that actually shows you how to set
up a shell script to do all this for you
so if you ever want to tweet something
or have some shortened URL or if you
want to snag one for your vanity URL
comm slash hold and stuff like that
that's nice way to do it check out all
these links in my talk later slides so
that's the recap really think through
this stuff this is the stuff that will
bite you further down the line unless
you really think it to reach time and
the problem is that you don't notice it
being a problem until it's too late and
then when you can't go back and fix it
so it's got to be a constant battle of
like what kind of group how can I make
my developers happier do I really need
all this extra stuff and then I think
you can make cool products so thanks