here we are again everybody is Tony and
Ian from Tektronix nice to see you guys
are back we're going to do a video on
FFT that's right the fast Fourier
transform okay
so just what is it the ends just a
different way of looking at your signal
on oscilloscopes we're used to looking
at voltage changing over time
FFT just shows you instead what voltages
are present at each frequency I get that
that's a good okay
so this is the kind of a clear way of
looking at this right if you can imagine
your signal as a bunch of wire tangled
together the FFT just helps you untangle
it and see what it's made up see what
components are lurking in that signal my
tangled hair exactly hey what are you
saying
yeah no you're okay okay I used
conditioner this morning come on so
let's say you're designing a circuit
you're going to send some RF energy out
an antenna so you're going to pull out
that into in a plug in a BNC cable
connect it to your scope now because
you're generating a sine wave you expect
to see the voltage changing sinusoidal e
over time and that would be represented
in the FFT by one spike because there's
one frequency exactly you got it already
happen excellent but imagine that you
plug this into what you actually see is
a second spike right here that is
excellent and you wouldn't see that
right there the sine wave because it's
so low level it's such a miniscule
second signal that you have to have
something like the FFT to bring it out
there's no way I could have seen that
and on a real scope you'd look and you'd
find out well if I'm expecting 900
megahertz and I got 1800 megahertz
that's a harmonic I probably have some
harmonic distortion there are other
causes and this isn't just Photoshop
this is this is this is real right there
either
arrows photoshopped I can't believe that
it's so good so there are some other
common causes of interference we're just
going to kind of let those sit on the
slide for a second so that after the end
of the video you can jump back here and
you thought it was harmonic because
where it was at exactly the frequent if
it were somewhere else maybe would have
been crosstalk from a clock signal
that's really handy so let's talk about
how it actually works there's this
beautiful property of mathematic
where every signal can be thought of as
the sum of a bunch of sine waves did you
hear him he said every sec any signal
you want any shape name is shave let's
do the square wave square wave by
coincidence that's what's on this next
card yes even yes Tony even a square
wave is the sum of a bunch of sideways
let's see how that works if we wanted to
make a square wave by adding together a
bunch of sine waves we'd start with a
single sine wave how smooth yeah very
smooth it's almost like we've done a
bunch of failed take to this video no
way so if we add a sine wave to nothing
we get a sine wave okay 1 2 1
I got it in it right and that would
cause a single spike to appear in the
frequency domain now we're going to add
a second sine wave that's 1/3 as tall
and it's been scaled in by 1/3 and this
is the mathematical part this is like
there's two humps within this big one
yes exactly when we add those two
together that's going to add a little
yeah as you say that's going to add a
little hump at the top and bottom of
each of these and in the frequency
domain here because it's two sine waves
that's two peaks so let's add a third
one instead of this one being scaled by
a third it's scaled by a fifth I see and
when we add that it's going to add even
more wiggles it's going to make the size
steeper it's going to make the tops and
bottoms flatter and you notice we're
kind of closing in on a square wave here
so then we go to a cell get squared up
here Oh terrible okay we're going to a
seventh and one night to 111th and so on
and so we keep adding Peaks until it
kind of vanishes down into the noise
floor oh yeah and we recognize that that
goes down like that
now let's hang on to this guard we'll
compare it with the real scope in a
minute okay so real world signals have
the same property they might look like a
tingle in the time domain and then a
nice neat shape well it's just probably
something here from
with lots of tangled signals yes how to
break them down so let's see this on our
real scope yeah let's take that away so
we're gonna see what this looks like on
a traditional oscilloscope first most
modern oscilloscopes have an FFT feature
they're usually the math system so we're
going to press math FFT and right away
you can see that signal tapering way off
down in the noise floor but let's zoom
in on that a little bit it's like in our
drawing right tapers off yes so you can
see that tapering off there in fact I'll
move it down a little bit sure you know
your way around this house cope don't
you this one feature I do so can we get
the card that we haven't you earlier
there you go you see that looks pretty
much like the FFT there I see that angle
and I see the angle all right genius
there's another class of instruments
that also do a lot of FFTs and that's
spectrum analyzers and this is so scope
the mixed domain oscilloscope has a
little bit of spectrum analyzer
personality built-in and it can do a
fifties as well mixed domain mix so many
things going together so we've got Italy
handy sorry okay we hope it is so we've
got one signal going to both the
traditional scope channel and this
dedicated spectrum analyzer channel I'm
going to turn that on oh and right away
you see a difference I do yeah
both types of views are right there
exactly we've got the frequency domain
view in a separate view and you can see
that second peak stands right out and
we've even marked it and identified that
it's spaced from the original 900
megahertz by 900 megahertz and it's down
about 25 dB so you put the marker in
here or did it mark it for you it marked
it for us so that tells us it's probably
harmonic distortion so this concludes
our video on FFT yes there's more right
there's more if you want to learn more
about FFTs you can go to Tektronix comm
slash FFT - basics and there's a lot of
stuff there yes and also stay tuned for
the next video of this series where we
do
FFT of a musical signal in front of a
live audience that sounds great see you
around okay thanks