in this video I'm going to explain the
2d Fourier transform in some sense the
2d Fourier transform is just a simple
and straightforward extension of the 1d
Fourier transform that you've been
learning about so far
unfortunately however it's not all that
simple
well implementing the 2d F of T really
is simple the problem is interpreting
the results of a 2d Fourier transform
and even more complicated is trying to
predict what an image might look like
based on its 2d FFT power spectrum first
let me explain how pictures are
represented on computers when you have a
picture like this your computer
represents this as a matrix and the
color in each little matrix element
corresponds to a number so in fact the
matrix looks like this and you can see
that larger numbers have darker colors
now when you have data organized in a
matrix like this the 2d FFT works by
first taking a one-dimensional FFT along
the columns of this matrix and this
produces a matrix of one dimensional
Fourier coefficients and that you can
see in this image frequency is on the y
axis the top row is the DC component and
all of these values are Fourier
coefficients for the Fourier transform
from each column the next step is to
perform a 1d FFT on the rows of this
matrix the result of this step is a two
dimensional matrix of Fourier
coefficients in this matrix the
low-frequency coefficients are around
the edges and the corners while the
Nyquist is at the center of the matrix
you'll recall that in a previous video I
showed that in some disciplines people
show the 1d power spectrum with DC in
the middle negative frequencies on the
left and positive frequencies on the
right for images shifting the
coefficients so that the Nyquist
frequency is at the edge
and the low frequencies are in the
middle is almost always done so
typically the image power spectra are
shown with low frequencies in the center
moving out towards higher frequencies
and Nyquist in the corner
computationally that's really all there
is to the 2d Fourier transform what's
tricky is figuring out how to map the
features of an image onto locations in
the 2d Fourier plane and you know when
people teach the 2d Fourier transform
they typically jump immediately straight
into showing power spectra of natural
images but I think it's better to start
with really simple images and first to
try to build a bit of intuition about
how to interpret the 2d Fourier plane
therefore what I'm going to do in the
rest of this video is show examples of
how spatial frequency phase and location
affect the 2d Fourier transform in
MATLAB I've set up a movie to illustrate
the relationship between frequency of a
2d sine wave and its representation in
the 2d Fourier plane before running this
simulation I'll show you the layout of
the main figure so this is the image
it's a 2d sine wave which is sometimes
also called a sine plane or a gradient
you can see that along this dimension
it's a sine wave and along this
dimension it's just straight lines this
is the 2d amplitude spectrum of this
image and this is the phase spectrum and
when I run this code you'll see that the
sine wave is going to change in
frequency over time as will the
amplitude and phase spectra and here
what I'm going to do is hold the phase
which is the orientation of this
gradient constant and change only the
spatial frequency this is like a real
scientific experiment where you hold as
many variables constant as possible and
you change only one variable at a time
in order to understand the effects of
that variable independent of all the
other variables
now you can watch this video and you can
see that as the spatial frequency of the
sine waves increases the peaks in the
amplitude spectrum move further away
from the origin I'll run it again
you can also see some changes in the
width of this peak but this is actually
not a really interesting feature it's
just due to the non-stationarity x'
related to the spatial frequencies
relative to the size of this image you
would see the same thing in the time
domain in the amplitude spectrum of a
sine wave that has non integer number of
cycles in the time window the phase
spectrum initially looks like it's
changing a lot and like it's really
granular and there's a lot of noise in
it but these are mostly just rounding
errors and you shouldn't pay too much
attention to them to understand where
these come from you can refer back to
the video about interpreting phase
values and the effects of uncertainty
and noise when the amplitude is close to
zero and you see from the amplitude
spectrum that the amplitude is basically
zero almost everywhere on this plane one
thing I'd like to mention about the
units of the spatial frequency that I
have here these are arbitrary numbers
that I picked because they happen to
look good on my computer screen
depending on your screen resolution
these values may or may not look good
so I encourage you to play around with
the lower and upper limits until you
find something that looks good on your
screen this was for sine waves with one
specific phase and it's interesting to
watch what happens when we change the
phase of this 2d sine patch now I'll
change the phase to be PI over four
you can see that the orientation has
changed and importantly the points on
the amplitude spectrum are moving on the
diagonal now instead of moving on this
line here but the behavior is exactly
the same they start close to the center
corresponding to low frequency sine
waves and then they move out towards the
edges in this case the corners as the
sine wave frequency increases I
encourage you to pause the video and
experiment with other phase values and
other spatial frequency ranges now for
the next experiment here I'm going to
hold the spatial frequency constant and
change the phase values over time so now
the sine patch will be just rotating
around as if it were the face of a clock
actually this would look pretty neat if
this were at the face of the clock now
notice what's happening in amplitude
spectrum the distance from the origin to
the peaks is staying the same but the
angle relative to the origin is changing
over time so this experiment is
complementary to the previous experiment
again I encourage you to pause the video
and rerun the code with different values
of spatial frequency and different sine
phases the third experiment is all about
spatial location here I'm using a
thresholded 2d gaussian to create a ball
that moves around on the plane the size
of the ball is constant and therefore
the spatial frequency of the ball is
constant only the spatial location of
the ball will change and now running
this code will show that the amplitude
spectrum isn't really changing but the
phase spectrum is changing in a way that
is well beautiful to look at but pretty
much impossible to interpret what I mean
by that is if I just showed you this
phase spectrum you might be able to
guess that the stimulus is a circle
based on the spatial pattern
of the phases but you wouldn't be able
to guess where in space the ball is I'll
tell you a little bit more about this
code just so you know enough to be able
to continue exploring it on your own the
circle is defined by this gaussian and
by this threshold which varies between 0
& 1
this determines the size of the circle
and here whatever values are subtracted
off of the x and y matrices correspond
to the center of the circle so in this
video I introduced you to the 2d Fourier
transform I explained mechanistically
how it works by applying the 1d Fourier
transform first to the columns of a
matrix and then to the rows of the
resulting fft coefficient matrix I then
showed several movies in MATLAB to help
you understand the relationship between
spatial frequency phase spatial location
and the results of the 2d Fourier
transform