the discrete Fourier transform is
fundamental to many questions in science
and technology and naturally we want to
be able to compute the discrete Fourier
transform fast the classical way to do
that is the so called FFT offer so the
FFT algorithms for the fast Fourier
transform algorithm was first designed
in 1965 by Cooley and two geeks it's
also known as cool into key algorithm
and has led to a revolution in digital
signal processing this is Michael
capitalist messaging professor of the IT
security PSL and it did the Fourier
transform is central to our information
age as a result performing the Fourier
transform in a fast and efficient manner
has been one of the greatest
breakthroughs of computer science
professor Draper's trying of MIG
described the fast Fourier transform as
the most important numerical algorithm
of our lifetime but why is the Fourier
transform so central to our modern world
those transfer was really fundamental to
numerous areas of science and technology
can think of signal processing data
analysis medical imaging and perhaps the
very well-known example of image and
video compression schemes so think of
JPEG do you know what JPEG is don't you
what about mp3 these are digital formats
for images and sounds and there are
plenty of other formats for videos as
well like h.264 which is the one I'm
using for this video search audio-visual
files are opened by each and every one
of us every day and every time you're
looking at a digital picture every time
you're listening to digital music and
every time you're playing a digital
video some FFT algorithm will be running
in the background as Richard Branagh a
professor of Rice University puts it FFT
over billions of times a day but how
does the Fourier transform help with
audio-visual compression in many
applications we acquire signals and
continues to me but these signals are
usually sampled at discrete intervals
analog to digital converter
so once the signal is digitized or
sampled the question becomes can we
compute the discrete Fourier transform
of that signal this is by opposition to
the classical continuous Fourier
transform that we studied by French
mathematician Joseph Fourier and others
in the early 1800s these days we rather
focus on digital data and that's all we
rather care about the discrete Fourier
transform now if we are trying to
compress an image using the JPEG method
what we would like to do is just say I
take an image I take the Fourier
transform of that image and then it
turns out that for most images because
these images are smooth in time domain
the Fourier domain representation is
fairly compact so just truncate to the
top few coefficients and magnitude zero
out the rest and hence we achieve
compression let's explain a bit more
signals like images and sounds can be
regarded as one way of representing some
fundamental mathematical objects the
free transform allows us to look at
these fundamental mathematical objects
through a different angle there by
objects that look awfully complicated in
the signal domain can suddenly appear
amazingly simple and easy to describe in
the Fourier co-main this will be the
case when the signal in the Fourier
domain is mostly zeros in which case we
don't even need to recall the zero
values we can just store in memory the
nonzero values which means that we need
less memory space to record our signal
but why would the fully a representation
of images and sound be so nice and
compact in the Fourier domain so if we
think of a case for signal and Fourier
domain all this is a signal that is
basically a sum of a small number of
pure harmonics plus mainly some amount
of noise and music it's pretty clear why
most music are made of only a handful of
pure harmony after all that's how music
partitions are written each height of a
musical note
imposes a particular pitch which
corresponds to a pure harmonics
in fact that's even more than that as
depending on instruments each note is
accompanied with a tone which is usually
itself a combination of a handful of
pure harmony however it might be less
clear why images are also made of a
handful of pure harmony the way JPEG
actually works is by first decomposing
an overall image into tiny squares now
if the resolution of the large image is
quite high each tiny square will likely
be smooth and nearly homogeneous which
means that the frequency representation
of such tiny squares will mostly be made
of low frequencies both cases it turns
out that most of the signal is actually
a composition of a handful of
frequencies now the other frequencies
they are usually not exactly zero
because there's always some noise but as
long as this noise these amplitudes of
the other frequencies are low and
negligible compared to the main signal
you can basically just get rid of them
just cancel them out without really
affecting the quality of the image of
the sound now the underlying idea of
JPEG is that we take a time domain
representation which is the image itself
we take the Fourier transform of that
and then it turns out but if we just
keep the top few coefficients and throw
away the rest the image almost doesn't
change and how to achieve compression
this approach has strong resemblance
with machine learning algorithms like
pca
or a DVD or like the word vector
representation we discussed with martin
Jaggi this is one reason why the
discrete fourier transform is important
because for natural signals that arise
and applications sort of concentrates
their energy in a small number of
coefficients and hence just focusing on
those coefficients on these coefficients
results in savings saying storage saying
time etc and the Fourier basis turns out
to also be convenient for other reasons
and one of these reasons is the fact
that
convolution the operation of convolving
two signals becomes very easy to perform
in the fury of the main wait what a
convolution and why does it matter
so here's one reason for computing
convolutions suppose that I have a
signal X and from template signal Y and
I know that a signal X is basically a
shift or maybe a shift of the signal Y
and time domain plus perhaps with some
annoyed added and what I want is to find
out what is the right shift basically
that aligns x and y optimally one way to
do it is exactly to compute a
convolution so what is a convolution
convolution is the following operation
we take the signal X let me consider all
the possible shift of the other signal Y
we do the dot product of X and the
shifted version of Y we're basically
overlay X with a shifted version of Y
and check how similar they are but why
would we ever want to search for the
optimal translation of X that best align
with Y and this is actually the
operation the GPS devices do when
they're receiving a GPS signal cigarette
does X perhaps a noisy version of some
temporal signal y yes because to locate
yourself using GPS you need to measure
very precisely the communication delay
from the satellite to your phone to do
so the satellite will send you a signal
Y and you know that it will look like
some template eggs
measuring the arrival time of Y resent
boolean to determining the time
translate of X that best matches the
signal Y and now the question is can you
find the right shift you know if you
think of doing this in the direct brute
force way if my signal X is of length on
my signal Y is of length n then I need
to try all the end ship on the other
hand so I can switch to the Fourier
domain turns out that all that I need to
do is take the Fourier transform of X
Fourier transform of Y and multiply them
point wise and then do the Fourier
transform back then in the resulting
signal if I look at the peak at the
maximum this is the right shift so
multiplication is very easy convolution
is very important so if we have a way of
quick
switching from time domain
representation to frequency domain
representation and we can take x and y
compute the Fourier transform multiply
them compute the Fourier transform back
and we have the convolution of x and y
so this is a fast algorithm for
performing convolution the Fourier
transform is a key algorithm to
determine optimal time translation
exactly so this is a very efficient way
of sort of yes resolving optimal
translations of one fragment but make it
similar to another citation more
generally whenever signals have a lot of
time or spatial translation symmetries
then convolution and the Fourier
transform will be powerful tools to
efficiently deal with such symmetries in
fact inspired by the architecture of a
brain researchers in deep learning have
exploited convolution to improve the
image processing of venule networks this
has led to so called convolutional
neural networks as well as key
breakthroughs in object detection and
face recognition so yes
the Fourier transform is a big deal but
the fact are also there are also other
reasons what we mention mention one to
you and this is something that comes up
in medical imaging for example when one
is performing MRI scan one can view this
process as follows so there's this
object being scanned the patient and
essentially the process of performing
MRI scan is that we can think of the
patient as a signal in time domain now
the MRI machine basically measures fully
efficient of the signal X at look at
various locations so now the question
becomes if I want to scan and scan a
signal X or a patient then this is
basically the question of reconstructing
X from the small number of fully a
measurements so this is yet another
application where the Fourier transform
comes up for completely different
reasons just is given by the feta crop
across and in fact this is not so
different from what our ears do at any
point in time for is or made of tiny
here each of which can only vibrate at a
very specific frequency now because of a
physical phenomenon called resonance all
hell will vibrate if and only if it
feels the pure harmonics associated with
its intrinsic frequency and when you
think about it this means that our
brains are only told about the
frequencies of the sounds that our ears
hear yet other enjoyable to combine
these frequencies to reconstitute the
sound that our ears hear our brains
apply the Fourier transform all the time
so in a nutshell the Fourier transform
has a lot a lot a lot of applications
with barely scratched the surface in
this video and because of it took the
fast Fourier transform by Korean Turkey
has conquered the world but what if I
were to tell you that Korean turkeys
algorithm has recently been out perfect
well this is what we shall discuss next
time
that's where the Fourier transform comes
in it comes up with a way to estimate
the functions on the whole real line
using complex Exponential's this
algorithm runs in time about log squared
n so it doesn't even look at the entire
signal